Chris Sanders

Digital Project Manager

chris.sanders72@gmail.com

Summary

A Toronto based digital professional with 7 years experience,

focused on Digital Strategy, UX/UI Design, Information Architecture, QA, SEO Consulting & Development for the web.

With experience & specialties that include: Project/Team Management, Information Architecture, UX/UI Design, Digital Strategy, Social Media Campaigns, Front-end Development, Search Engine Optimization, Ad Sense, Database Design, Lead Generation, Gamification, AB / Multivariate Testing, Blogging, Writing, Social Media and Digital Campaign roll-outs.

Experience

Web Content Manager - Integrated Marketing at WE

August 2017 - Present

Project Manager, Consultant, UX/UI Designer, Information Architect, Front-End Developer January 2011 - Present

Specializing in User Experience (UX) and User Interface (UI) design web-development information architecture, search engine optimization (SEO), quality assurance (QA) and analytical development. I consult with small businesses to understand their business objectives and develop analyses to support decision making regarding their digital marketing and branding needs. This is accomplished through indepth business analysis in order to set specific mile-stones in order for them to grow their business within the digital space.

Digital Project Manager at Craft + Keen

January 2017 - March 2017 (3 months)

Technical Manager - Creative & Communications at WE

January 2016 - January 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Leading WE's internal team of 12 web developers on the WE.org, ME to WE, Track Your Impact, WE Day and WE Charity brands - I collaborate with internal stakeholders to strategize, create, achieve and maintain the organizations digital goals. This includes the re-brand from Free The Children > WE and working with the team to implement new UX/UI standards across the organizations various sites. - Helping drive/modernize the development team through the introduction of an agile team work-environment, running daily

scrums on daily/weekly product sprints. While continuing to establish strong working relationships with internal stakeholders by managing expectations for web updates and project status.

WE.org
MEtoWE.com
TrackYourImpact.com
WECharity.org
WEDay.com
WE.ca

UX/UI Designer / Front-end Developer at Tribute Entertainment Media Group

September 2015 - November 2015 (3 months)

3-month contract position working along side back-end development team / internal stakeholders with a focus on UX/UI Design, Branding, Rapid Prototyping, Information Architecture as well as Front-end Development for movie releases & contest promotion.

Projects included:

Internal Websites - Tribute.ca & Showtimes.com

External Websites / Movie Promotion: Sony Pictures and Warner Bros Pictures

Digital Manager at Zync Agency

January 2015 - May 2015 (5 months)

UX & Information Architecture, building high fidelity wire-frames, sitemaps using MyBalsamiq & Slick Plan. Web development as well as deploying advanced analytical and SEO strategies for multiple legacy client websites, while creating organic SEO documentation for clients via audits, keyword optimization, sitemap development and competitive market analysis. This included cross browser/device testing, user tester strategies, AODA compliance while coordinating with developers internally as while as remote to ensure that projects were delivered within the project scope. Often acting as a liaison for client communication, translating technical communication into non-technical insights to both key stakeholders and clients alike.

Notable Clients:

Canadian Olympic Committee

Aviva Canada - avivawaterprotection.ca

Weston Premium Woods - westonpremiumwoods.com

GEOTECH - geotech.ca

Real Estate Council of Ontario - reco.on.ca

Armtec - armtec.com

salonmsquared.ca

caho-hospitals.com

Digital Manager at 52 Pick-up Inc.

June 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 7 months)

Leading the digital team of web developers and interactive designers, I collaborate to create and achieve client / company goals, creating comprehensive marketing campaigns through digital innovation. Helping drive the Digital team and continue to establish strong working relationships with clients by managing expectations for web/digital updates and project status. In addition, to meeting with clients to present new website creative, information architecture, user experience and provide recommendations for site functionality.

Provide project briefs to members of digital team and designers for digital projects. Defining project timelines and scopes for all 52 Pick-up's digital projects, creating project estimates, critical paths, work-back schedules and proposals for new and legacy clients.

Collaborate with digital designers and VP of Strategy on creating information architecture and user experience documentation (wireframes, sitemaps) for digital projects.

Assist digital team when needed with Front-end development tasks such as coding, deployment of e-blasts, updates to legacy websites (HTML, CSS, PHP), QA / browser testing. Review and provide feedback for web projects throughout the entire process (discovery, information architecture, design, development, QA and launch).

Coordinate with freelancers for help on digital projects and ensure quality of work and project deadlines are met by web developers, QA testers etc. Collaborate with Principals, Account Executives / Managers, VP of Strategy, Social Media Coordinator, Digital Team and Designers on creating comprehensive marketing campaigns Work with Social Media Coordinator to implement social media tools and campaigns into the interactive space.

Provided ongoing campaign analysis and recommendations by generating dashboards, standardized reports and developing complex analytical models to ensure maximum effectiveness of the digital elements of all marketing campaigns.

Front End Web Developer at 52 Pick-up Inc.

June 2012 - October 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Building responsive site designs using HTML 5 / CSS 3 to ensure ease of use across all devices while still maintaining cross-browser compatibility. Sites incorporate server side programming languages such as PHP, MySQL and SQL. Experience with maintaining a custom CMS as well as building websites with industry standard CMS' such as WordPress. Sites are optimized to ensure the best results in search engines, using Google SEO/SEM tools such as Analytics, AdWords and Webmaster tools. Helping to create an enriched online experience for the end-user(s), using custom AJAX, JQuery and JavaScript. Creating /deploying

e-blasts and SEM strategies to better reach the target audience/demographic and aid digital marketing strategies. Working with a Social Media Coordinator to implement social media tools / campaigns into the interactive space.

Notable Clients:

trinitysf.com

mainandmain.ca

tcgpr.com

52pick-up.com

streetcar.ca

genesisland.com

lindvest.ca

harmonyvillage.ca

lakeviewhomes.ca

thekipdistrict.com

Front-End Developer at Mediavanta

January 2012 - June 2012 (6 months)

Developing "Pixel Perfect" HTML/ CSS Templates for CMS websites for clients mainly created using the LAMP stack via PHP / WordPress.

Working on PC in Notepad++, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks) & SVN/ FTP Clients for Launch

Projects Included:

chie-bcei.ca

chancefoundation.ca

Multimedia Lab Advisor / Peer Tutor

September 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 4 months)

Tutor and assess students' performance, competency and knowledge within the digital and social media, marketing & material design and show that through demonstrated tasks they meet the required standards as per the content they are studying.

Electronics CSR at Walmart

June 2009 - August 2011 (2 years 3 months)

My first experience in Retail Sales for TVs, Computers, Tablets and Video Game Systems. Related Inventory & stock. Ensuring effective team work, sales strategy, customer service as well as aiding loss prevention.

Shift Manager, Server, Cook, Driver at Pizza Hut

May 2004 - August 2009 (5 years 4 months)

My first job(s) where I learned to manage people, their expectations, product quality, good service, inventory, accounting, scheduling and the mastery of making the perfect pizza.

Education

Confederation College

Advanced Diploma, Interactive Media Development - (Multimedia Production), 2009 - 2012 **Activities and Societies:** Ontario Colleges Advisory Committee, Deans List

Honors and Awards

Featured Speaker

Chris Sanders

Digital Project Manager

chris.sanders72@gmail.com



Contact Chris on LinkedIn